Alfred F. Bochenek collection of American Council of Polish Culture records 1971-1996 CPAA 02-01
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain
Alfred F. Bochenek collection of American Council of Polish Culture records
1971-1996
Alfred F. Bochenek
CPAA 02-01
2 boxes (2 linear ft.)
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
Collection consists of records of the American Council of Polish Culture (ACPC) compiled by Mr. Alfred Bochenek during his active participation in the organization. It covers the timespan of 1971 to 1996. The name of the organization changed in 1988 from American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC) to American Council for Polish Culture (ACPC). Within this collection we refer to the organization as ACPCC and ACPC to reflect the change in the name. Extensive correspondence and membership information illustrate activities of the council from 1971 till 1996
Biographical Note
Mr. Alfred F. Bochenek was born in 1914 in Springfield, Massachusetts. He graduated from the US Coast Guard Academy, worked as an engineer in numerous companies and was a strong advocate for greater awareness of Polish contributions to U.S. history and culture. Mr. Bochenek was active in local and national Polish American organizations and served as an officer of the Polish American Arts Association of Washington DC and the American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs, which awarded him its Founder's Award in 1988. Mr. Bochenek was a long time chairmen of the Award Committee of American council of Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC). He authored a pamphlet entitled, “American Polonia, the Cultural Issues: What are the National Goals of Polish America and How are These to be Defined?” It was published by the ACPCC in 1981.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Alfred F. Bochenek was very active in the American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs for almost three decades from the 1970's untill the 1990's. The collection contains papers from annual conventions, correspondence, constitution and by-laws, and membership lists. Material in this collection complements related records from other collections donated by various individuals who were active in the organization. Because of the name change of the organization in 1988 folder descriptions have both names ACPCC - American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs and ACPC - American Council for Polish Culture but this is still the same organization.
The collection is open for research.
Collection was donated by Mrs. Anna Bochenek, wife of Alfred F. Bochenek, after his death in 2002.
Search Terms
Bochenek, Alfred F.; American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs; American Council for Polish Culture -- History.; Polish Americans -- Societies, etc.; American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs -- History.; Conventions.; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.
Related Material
For related material from Connecticut Polish American Archives see the following collections: Amarican Council for Polish Culture records CPAA 96-03 Joseph L. Zazyczny collection of American Council of Polish Culture records CPAA 99-15
Arrangement
Mr. Alfred Bochenek kept the ACPCC files in a chronological order and the original arrangement is kept within the collection.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- ACPCC-Campaign to sponsor Polish language course at the Washington University in D.C., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ACPCC-Convention - clippings from Polish-American Press, June 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ACPCC-Bicentennial Poster contest., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ACPCC-The Year of Copernicus - related material, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ACPCC-and the Polish-American Arts Association of Washington D.C.-correspondence, announcements, clippings., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ACPCC-Annual convention-president's minutes., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- ACPCC-Alfred F. Bochenek - a biographical sketch September 19, 1975, and obituary., March 14, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ACPCC- awards and correspondence., 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- ACPCC-correspondence., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ACPCC-constitution and by-laws, June 1975, August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ACPCC-Awards., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- ACPCC-correspondence., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- ACPCC-28th Annual Convention, Rosemont College-reports, minutes., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- ACPCC-poster sales record and related correspondence., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- ACPCC-Kosciuszko Project-related correspondence., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ACPCC-correspondence., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- ACPCC-Constitution and By-laws., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- ACPCC-clubs list and executive board., 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ACPCC-correspondence, announcements., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- ACPCC-American Youth of Polish Descent-related correspondence, brochures., 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ACPCC-exploratory meeting, and related materials., May 12, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- ACPCC-National conference committee pt.1., 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- ACPCC-correspondence, newsletters, announcements., 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- ACPCC-regional discussion meeting Buffalo (Photographs), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- ACPCC-Alfred Bochenek correspondence., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- ACPCC-press release on panel discussion on cultural issues concerning American Polonia (in Polish and English), April 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- ACPCC-exploratory meeting, and related materials., May 12, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- ACPCC- National conference committee-correspondence, January-June 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- ACPCC-solicitation letters on behalf of ACPCC by Alfred Bochenek re: regional discussion meetings on Polonia., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ACPCC-press releases., 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- ACPCC- correspondence., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- ACPCC-list of addresses of board members and directors/affiliates., 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- ACPCC-National Conference Committee correspondence., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- ACPCC-National Conference Committee correspondence., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- ACPCC-correspondence., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ACPCC-Grant proposal from National center for urban ethnic affairs., April 1, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- ACPCC-correspondence., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ACPCC-Young Americans of Polish Descent (YAPD)4th Annual convention "Leadership through participation"., August 10-14, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- ACPCC-correspondence., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- ACPCC-correspondence, press releases., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- ACPCC-correspondence, announcements, press releases., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- ACPCC-correspondence, clippings., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- ACPCC-Polish American Arts Association of Washington D.C.-memberships applications., 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- ACPC-constitution and by-laws., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- ACPC-Board of directors list., 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- ACPC-National convention in Philadelphia - correspondence, financial reports, minutes., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- ACPC-"Polish contributions to the United States" by Wanda Tomczykowska., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- ACPC-board meeting minutes, announcements and correspondence., 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- ACPC- constitution and by-laws., 1990 and 1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- ACPC-proposals for musical events., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- ACPC-directory., 1981-1983, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- ACPC-blank stationary., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- ACPC-membership list., [1992] (Box 2, Folder 29)
- ACPC-membership and related correspondence., 1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- ACPC-membership and related correspondence., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- ACPC-membership and related correspondence., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- ACPC-membership and related correspondence., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- ACPC-membership and related correspondence., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- ACPC-List of subscribers to the Polish Heritage., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- ACPC-membership cards., 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 36)